Hello everyone welcome back to the channel, I am
Vishwajeet and I welcome you to your
own YouTube channel Doctor Asset. Today we will
talk about ICICI Lombard General
Insurance Company and see
what the fundamentals and technicals say about this
company. Before proceeding further, let me tell you one
thing that this video is only for
educational purposes. If you
take any position in the company, then you
must consult your financial advisor. So, let's
start by knowing about the company.
First of all, we will know
what the company does.
According to me, the best way to know about the company is its website.
Everything can be known on its website itself. So let's see what is the status of
its
business.
Looking here, it seems that this is an
insurance company. If we talk about insurance also, then
looking here, it has
4 crore customers. So, the trust of 4
crore customers is still on it. If we
talk about policy suits, then
it has
2.17 crore policies and if we talk about
claim settlement, then  There is a
network of 1.6 million. If we talk about garages, then
they have a network of 11400 plus. If we
talk about health care providers, they have more than 6700
health care providers. So let's
talk further about what the company does. So
looking at here, it seems that there is tax insurance,
bike insurance, health insurance, travel
insurance, cyber insurance.
Motor insurance has tax
insurance, bike insurance and motor
floater. Just like there is a
family floater,
they have also issued a motor floater. What
happens in this is that if I have a
scooter, a bike, a car, and if there is a
tractor or a truck in my name, then we can do it by
grouping all of them under one policy number
so that it is easy for us to track
and make the payment once. If we
do it in different policies and keep different policy
numbers, then doing this and that again and again,
sometimes there is a problem in making the payment. That is
why the company has issued a motor
floater in the name of motor floater itself.
You can do it under that and come and see
what they have. So they have health
insurance, you can see in health insurance.
They have health insurance in different categories. If we talk about the same further, then
they have travel insurance as well, which would be for
single trip,
then student travel nowadays. We can see that
nowadays we can see that many
people are very keen to go abroad, so the desire to
go abroad is big among our youth,
so if you go abroad to any
country like Paris, Vietnam
or Dubai etc., then
you must have travel insurance for that. If you do
not have travel insurance, then
your visa will not be approved. So for this
they have travel insurance as well. Let's
talk further about what the company does.
They have business insurance.
In business insurance, you can see that there is marine insurance, there is
group health insurance, there is fire insurance,
after that,
we also call it marine insurance, fire insurance,
then they have housing society
insurance. If we talk about this, then
they have very good insurance for professional medical practitioners as well. If
we talk about insurance further, then
what else does the company do, then they have crop
insurance, NR insurance, cyber
insurance and many more. Complete home
protection.  The question is insurance, so
from all this we can see that
they have a lot, if we talk about crop insurance, then
they have Pradhan Mantri Fasal Bima Yojana,
so they have everything which can be
very effective in the days to come and this
sector has a lot of scope, so according to me,
today they have every thing, every
insurance whose scope has increased a lot,
if we talk about the product in crop insurance also,
then everything is the same,
they have given all the same things in a good
form, so
because of it being online, everything has become very neat
and clean, now if anyone can make
any claim or can do the policy
registration, then before we
talk about the company further,
I would like to tell you one thing, let me
show you some data, the data is of per
capital, if we talk about the per capital option, then
in the per capita option, if we talk about New Zealand,
United States, Poland, Iceland, then
we take the United States, if we
talk about the United States even now, then the
population of 868 vehicles per 1000 is
in the United States, the same is the case with our state  If we
talk about it, our state is far behind.
In this case, for a minute, our state
was approximately 60. If we talk about our state, then
you can clearly see the per capita income of
our state here, which is 62
vehicles per 1000 population. I am
showing you this data because it has a direct
link with the insurance company. The more the number of
vehicles increases, the more will be the number of
policies. People will get more insurance
and the more insurance they get,
the more will be their benefit and
when there is a benefit, it will definitely be reflected in the price,
in its share price. We will show you one more data, let us
talk about it first. This is of
health insurance, which you can
clearly see here that it
was 2.7 percent in 2001, which increased to 3.76%
in 2019. If we talk about the global average, then right now
we are far behind the global average from
7.23%, which is the survey of 2021, 20 and
21. So we  You can see that the sector
in which this company works, it still has a lot of shares left
in that sector
and now as we are talking about, even now
our majority of shares, that is
sorry, I mean, the people who live in our villages
and areas, then according to
me, there are
very few people who prefer to take insurance
and there might be
two-three percent living in villages too, but the
majority of the population still
lives in villages and the population which is there now has
insurance, so even now it can be a very
good market place for these companies, they
can target there, if we talk about our
place, then in urban areas now people have become cautious
and have started taking health insurance,
still the insurance character is quite under-
penetrated, there is still a
lot left to penetrate it, so let us talk about it, now
we come directly to the fundamental analysis of the company, so first of all we will
start with the
market capitalization, if we talk about the market cap, then the
market cap
is Rs 56726 crore, if we talk about the company's market
capitalization current price, then  Its value
is 1156. If we talk about the last 12 months i.e. 1 year, then
its high is 1548 and its low is 1071. If we look at the
stock journey, then the
approximate book value is 203, the
dividend yield is
0.78%, which is very good. If we
talk about Aarushi, it is 19.2, which is a little low. Generally,
I prefer to
invest in stocks with shares above 30%, but here,
if the opportunity is good, then a little
compromise can be made. The promoter
holding is 98%, the rate is equal to zero. There is
no profit. If we look at the last 12 months, the
roll is 406 and the industry is p67, so
if the industry is 67 and the stock is p36, then it is
available at a very high price. Let me
tell you one more thing, if
you want to read more about this company, then you can read it
thoroughly by clicking on Read More from here.
Once you
click on Read Mode here, you will get complete details about it.
Read it once, let's
move ahead and talk about the quarterly results. If
we look at the quarterly results, if we
talk about sales in the quarterly results, then
in September 19, that is, the
sales of 2018, which has now increased to
sales of 469 crores.
Talking about net profit, the net profit has
increased from 38 crores to 50091 crores. So the
quarterly result has been presented very well by the
company. There is a very good improvement in sales as well. There is a
very good improvement in net profit as well.
After the quarterly results, we move ahead
towards profit and loss. We will
calculate the profit and loss on year basis. It is about
2011, in 2010, where the
company used to
sell 56 crores in 2018, which is now
selling 1626 crores in March 2022.
Talking about the last trailing 12 months, the highest ever was
16000 825  It has done sales of crores. If we
talk about profit before tax, then
profit before tax was ₹82 crores
in 2011, which has now increased to ₹
14648 crores and if we talk about trailing 12 months, then it has
reached ₹10906 crores. If
we talk about net profit, then net
profit is ₹80 crores, where at one time the company was
in loss, which has now increased to ₹1271 crores
and if we talk about trailing 12 months, then it has become ₹
1570 crores. Talking about dividend, if we
talk about CAGR of the company, then if we talk about five years, then the
company is growing at 11%. If we
talk about share capital in the balance sheet, then the
company has ₹45 crores from share capital
in March 11, which has now increased to ₹491
crores.
You can see that the
share capital increases only because of the company's state being diluted,
but still this
money remains with the company. Talking about reserves, then the
reserves are ₹
1026 crores.  So in March 11, which has now
increased to
₹945 crores, if we talk about 12th, then the
growth of Borrowing Boring Company was
in March 17, which is negligible now. If we
talk about necklace, then there is no current working
progress right now and if we talk about investment, then the
investment of the company has gone up to
around ₹465 crores 96 crores. If we talk further, if we talk about
cash flow activity, then the
company is presenting present cash flow in positive,
which is negative
65 crores, the company is presenting in positive. If we
talk about share holding factor, then
in the share holding pattern, the promoters used to
hold majority stake at one time in 2019 with 55.86%, which at present
promoters have 48.2%, which is approximately
around 7%. If we talk about the company having
diluted,
then it had 24%
in December 19, which is still approximate to 24%, we will
say 24.7% 24 points.  Talking about the indirect 24%,
DD had 12.53% which has now
increased to
15.8%.
DD has maintained
its position and has kept
its position constant. Similarly, the
government has also increased its stake in this company by
0.9% in the latest quarter in September.
Talking about the public, the public had 7.6% which has
now increased to 11.92% in December 19. So,
increasing any shareholding with the public is not a good thing. But if
we look at the public by bifurcating it and see
how much the public has now, then
here we will see that the public
still has
3.71% which is with Bhartiya General Ventures Private
Limited. So
overall the company is around 7%
with the public, so this is a very good sign.
One good thing here is that the majority
shareholder is the promoter, which is a
very good thing for the company. If
we look at all this shareholding pattern, then the
company has a very good healthy balance.  The
holding sheet has a very good welding
pattern, the cash flow is positive, the balance
sheet is very healthy and if we talk about profit and loss, that is
also good and the
company is making profits quarter after quarter, so
these parameters are seen
in the fundamental analysis, further we will talk about the
technical analysis of the company, so
before the technical analysis, we
would like to tell you once that we forgot one thing, here you
can see that this
company has acquired Indian General
Insurance, which has also now become a subsidiary
of ICICI Lombard, so once
we click and see what this
company does, we will also know what the company does,
if we click here and see,
in To No More, this company also does the same things
that ICICI Lombard does, so in a way,
it also has car insurance,
bike insurance, health
insurance and this company also does travel,
cyber insurance, they also have
policy suit, if we talk about it, then it is 27.1 million, their
claims settled is 1.6, then if we talk about it
Their network of garages is also more than
10,000. And if we talk about health care providers, then
65 means above 6,500. So this
company also used to do the same work, but what did it do at a smaller
level? This is what happens,
companies keep doing it with each other so that
now when the results come next time, the
money that was less than this will go into the balance sheet of its
parent company, i.e. ICICI Lombard, and the
balance sheet will become even
better. Now we will talk about this.
After this, this was our fundamental
analysis. Now let's see what signals are coming on the technicals.
Talking about technicals, first of all we will open Trading View.
In Trading View, we will see
ICICI General Insurance.
You can see its symbol, this is it.
First of all, we will just do the chart once,
after that, some technicals will be created in front of you. From
here we can see that if we make
it a little smaller, then from
here let's
see where the company is with the red line. So,
we click on the red line and make it a
little bigger.
Okay, very good. Let's
now talk about the company. The
company is still trading at a strong support. The
company is trading at a strong
support, like, let's see this. Let's see this. If we
talk further, this is a very old
support line. Three was there. This is here.
3. This is here. 4. This is here. 6. So, the
company has respected its support very well almost six times.
So now let's talk about the
company. According to me, the company is
also trading at a very good support. Talking about
its targets, if we talk about the targets,
first of all, its short term target will be this. The
first target will be this. If we talk about the second target, it
got a rejection from here. If we talk about the
second target, then the target for the company will be
here. And if we talk about the fourth target, then the
target for the company will be here and the final
target
is here. So, if we ask me how long I am going to
hold this company, then according to me,
such companies are very rare because these
promoters are in very good hands. The
company's shares are in very strong hands.
If we look at the total, there is still an increase of 44%.  It
is left because according to me if the company
posts lifetime high quarterly results with revenue and profit
and net profit will also be the highest ever and
you can see in the price that it is still on the upside
then the company share price always
follows price reflection so here
according to me we will exit it at
lifetime high and that too as I have
two accounts so I will
exit in the trading account at lifetime high
but if you ask about long term
target then according to me such
companies are very few we can
give place in our portfolio for 10 years 20 years
if the company always keeps presenting good quarterly results and
yearly results then
see what will happen later we have added this company to
our portfolio for long term
so this is our technical and fundamental
analysis of ICICI Lombard if
you liked the video then do
share it with your friends subscribe to our channel
and like it let's
meet in some other video thank you bye take
care